■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：小饭  四方虾  王大可  冰蓝  丁小七
时间轴：浓子   校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第十五集
今天是我们家重要的一天
Okay, big day for this household.
没错  好激动
It certainly is. So exciting.
什么都比不上开始一个新工作
Nothing like starting a new job.
或是终于能在已有的工作中充分施展才能
Or finally coming into your own at a job you already have.
新事物带来的美好承诺
The promise of something new.
回报终于...
The rewards finally being --
相反的事情却一样地美好
Opposite things being equally good.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Yes.
我刚接受了一份在CFJ的工作
I have accepted a job at the C.F.J.,
也就是司法中心
The -- the Center For Justice.
不  那其实是一个
Not, it turns out,
超级英雄们的秘密总部
a secret headquarters for superheroes.
没有啦  算是吧
No, it -- it kind of is.
那是我在法学院的一个朋友
It's a legal-aid society
建立的一所司法救援团体
founded by a law-school friend of mine.
我将成为人民的律师
I will be an advocate for the people,
为无法发言的人发言
a voice for the voiceless.
一样重要的是
And just as important...
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
今晚  我将主持"春季叮当嘉年华"
Tonight, I am chaperoning the Spring-A-Ding-Fling,
筹款  舞会
a fundraiser, a dance,
在我的带领下
which, under my stewardship,
已经打破了学校记录
has shattered school records.
我还加了"叮当"
And I added the "A-ding."
以前一般就叫春季嘉年华
It used to just be called the Spring Fling.
我应该先说我的事情
I should have said my thing first.
各位
Hey, guys.
我今晚开场穿这身  说实话
For my opening number tonight -- be honest.
能看出来我在下面穿了别的吗
Does it look like I have anything on under this?
今晚就是SCARB之夜
Tonight is the SCARB.
南加州房地产经纪人年会
Southern California Annual Realtors' Banquet.
这是南加州房地产经纪人的盛会
It is the banquet for southern California realtors.
说真的  唯一的盛会
Literally, it's the only one.
而这家伙主持了两次
And this guy is the only two-time host --
三次
Three-time.
三次宴会  史上唯一一人
three-time host in the history of the event.
不幸的是  我今年无法参加了
Unfortunately, I have to miss it this year.
这样也好
It's for the best.
她在这种场合总是被无视
She's invisible at these things.
嫁给大明星就是这么不容易
It's tough being married to the rock star.
幸运的是  我另找了一个伴侣
Luckily, I lined up a substitute date.
老爸  你还没睡
Dad. You're still up.
是啊  还在想宴会上要讲的段子
Yeah, just working on some jokes for the banquet.
你跟我一起去怎么样
Hey, how'd you like to come with me?
当然好了
I would love to!
她会答应我毫不意外
Not surprised she said yes.
那丫头天生懂房产
That girl's got real estate in her blood.
她小时候常常跟着我
She used to come with me to open houses
去带客户看房
when she was little.
我们甚至还谈过
We may have even talked about
父女档一起合作呢
a father/daughter partnership.
是啊  她最近有些偏离正轨
Yeah, she's been drifting a little lately,
但让她感受一下
but I think a taste
地区房地产经纪人的魅力之夜
of regional real-estate's most glamorous night
也许能重新燃起她的激情
might just re-ignite that flame.
难以置信我居然得去参加这种宴会
I can't believe I have to go to this thing.
但我有什么选择呢
But what choice did I have?
我当然愿意
I would love to!
但你不会吃饼干不配牛奶吧
But you're not gonna have those cookies without milk, right?
对噢
Right.
不给力啊  菲尔
Come on, Phil.
休息区
Break area.
复印机
Copier.
我的小臭狗
My stinky dog.
瞧瞧啊
Oh, look at you.
你刚刚吐了一地
You just threw up recently. Okay.
我的天呐
Oh, my gosh.
那是你和米歇尔・奥巴马
That's you and Michelle Obama.
那是我姨
That's my aunt.
真抱歉
I am so sorry.
我不知道我为什么会以为
I don't know why I thought that --
淡定  别有什么白人内疚感
Calm down, white guilt.
那就是米歇尔・奥巴马
It's Michelle Obama.
太好了
Oh, good, yeah.
是啊  这15年你成就了很多啊
Yeah, you've accomplished a lot in 15 years.
在事业上是的
Professionally, yeah.
我已经六个月没有约会了
I haven't had a date in six months.
有时候周日我会开车去看看我的冷冻卵子
Some sundays, I drive out to visit my frozen eggs.
但是从好的一面来说
But, on the plus side,
我跟我妈妈非常亲密
I have gotten really close with my mom.
看那照片  我都看出相似之处了
Oh, look at that. I see the resemblance.
那是马娅・安杰卢
That's Maya Angelou.
该死
Damn it.
上面有签名  米奇
It's signed, Mitch.
对  我看到了
Yeah. I see that.
我们合作会很有意思的
This is gonna be fun!
是啊
I know!
-我真的非常期待  -你
- I'm just really looking for - You!
昨晚那身衣服算怎么回事
What was that outfit last night?
那可是商务晚宴
That was a business dinner!
你到底怎么回事
What is wrong with you?
温迪  我尽力了
Wendy, I tried.
那就更努力一点啊
Well, try harder.
这是你的办公室
Ooh, here's your office.
好的
Okay.
真不错啊
Oh, this is nice.
是啊  丹尼斯以前也很喜欢
Yeah. Dennis liked it...
后来就不喜欢了
until he didn't.
我过会儿再来找你
I'll check on you later.
好  好的
Okay. All right.
来看看
Let's see here.
[快跑]
新来的吗
New guy?
是啊  你好  我叫米奇尔・普里契特
Uh, yes. Hi. I'm Mitchell Pritchett.
我是丹
Dan.
希望你周日晚上没有安排
Hope you don't have any plans for Sunday night.
丹  你怎么还在这里
Dan! What are you still doing here?
快走啊
Go!
抱歉
Sorry.
没错
Right.
那边
That way!
不是吧
Oh, no.
[离开  否则你会死的]
我很喜欢皮革的
I do love it in leather.
那就试着喜欢丝绸的
Well, learn to love it in silk.
穿皮革出去太热了
It's too hot outside to be wearing leather.
我是说这辆车
I'm talking about this car.
顺便说一句
Oh, by the way,
今天去经销商那里  我来讲价
I do the negotiating at the dealership today.
为什么
Why?
亲爱的  我是生意人
Honey, I'm a businessman.
跟人打交道
When it comes to people,
我知道该怎么从他们那里得到我想要的
I know how to get what I want out of them.
这块表
This watch --
那家伙最后是半价卖给我的
The man sold it to me for half of what he was asking.
这鞋  三分之一
These -- a third.
这些  是免费的
These -- for free.
你说谁更会说服人  生意人先生
So, who's better at working people, Mr. Businessman?
好吧  我们方法不同
Fine. We have different approaches,
但我们都很厉害
but we're both pretty good.
喂  米奇
Hello, Mitch.
小子
Hey, buddy.
你看起来像是要站起来走路啊
You look like you want to get up and walk.
大器晚成  好吧
Late bloomer -- fine.
谁在乎别人家的小孩
Who cares if the other kids
叫你"慢吞吞的乔"呢
call you "Slo-Joe"?
他们就是这样叫你的
And they do, you know.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
我们得下次再去买车了
We're gonna have to reschedule the car shopping.
米奇得去工作
Mitch has to work.
小卡得去跳舞
Cam has to dance.
我们得照看莉莉
We have to sit Lily.
-怎么了  -没啥
- What? - Nothing.
只是...换做我的话就能推掉这件事
Just -- I could have got us out of that.
住手
Stop!
-吃掉  -从我身上下去
- Eat it! - Get off me!
吃草吧  牛儿
Eat the grass, cow!
-朗达  -您好  邓菲太太
- Hi, Rhonda. - Hi, Mrs. Dunphy.
妈妈
Hey, mom.
亲爱的  舞会就快开始了
Honey, it's getting very close to time for the dance.
你不该进屋去换衣服吗
Shouldn't you go in and get changed?
我已经换了
I did already.
他们在来的路上
The guys are coming by.
我们从这里骑车去
We're gonna ride from here.
你呢  朗达
What about you, Rhonda?
要进屋去把自己弄干净吗
You want to go in and get cleaned up?
-我没事  -是吗
- I'm good. - Are you?
你脸上还有泥巴呢
What about that dirt on your face?
卢克  你在这等着
Luke, you wait here.
和你朋友们骑车去
Ride with your friends.
我带朗达去  来吧
I will bring Rhonda. Come on.
进屋之前像狗那样
Just, um, give me a good shake like a dog
好好抖抖身上的泥巴
before you go inside.
我就知道
I know.
我爸爸有三处纹身
And my dad has three tattoos.
为啥啊  你都是当爹的人了
Like, "Why? You're a dad."
父母想要跟上潮流真是太可悲了
Ew! It's so sad when parents try.
我妈又在耳朵上打了耳洞
My mom double-pierced one of her ears,
我说  拜托
and I'm like, "Hello!
您都50了
You're 50."
这把年纪还打耳洞简直老到掉渣
It's so old, like, ancient to have an ear piercing.
你俩决定去舞会了吗
Uh, you two decide to go to the dance?
是啊  但不是认真地去
Well, yeah, but not really.
-但我们要去  -什么
- But, yeah. - What?
我们要带着讽刺态度过去
We're going ironically
嘲笑所有把这事看得很重的孩子们
to make fun of all the kids who make a big deal out of it.
讽刺个屁啊
"Ironic"? My ass.
艾丽克斯喜欢德鲁
Alex likes Drew.
她只是在打安全牌
She's just playing it safe.
有那种鲁莽讨厌的妈妈
Now, there are the pushy, obnoxious moms
喜欢卷入其中
who try and get involved,
为他们撮合撮合
nudge them towards one another.
我们是好意
We mean well.
衬衫不错啊  塔克教练
Fancy shirt, coach Tucker.
谢谢  你知道我喜欢说什么
Oh, thank you. You know what I like to say.
我可能是教练[二等舱]
I might be coach,
但我坐头等舱
but I travel first class.
你想不想
So, what would you think
在今晚的舞会上致开幕词啊
about giving the opening remarks at the dance tonight?
艺术委员会从来没有取得这么大的成就
The arts committee has never made this much,
这全都是因为你
and it's all because of you.
各位  我六个月前来到这所学校时
Oh, you guys, when I came to this school six months ago,
从没想到你们会敞开怀抱接纳我
I never would have imagined you would embrace me.
抱歉  这里是化学实验室吗
Excuse me? Is this a chem lab?
因为我在期待"大反应"
Because I'm looking for a big reaction.
这就有了
And there it is.
大家好啊
Hi. How are --
这位是谁啊
Who is this?
休假过得怎么样
How was sabbatical?
棒极了
Amazing.
我准备好...
I'm rested and ready...
度另一个假了
...to take another vacation.
他怎么称呼啊
And how are we supposed to know him?
卡普兰先生  传奇的西班牙语老师
Senor Kaplan, legendary Spanish teacher.
我有点同情他
You know, my heart went out to him a little
因为他离开时还是大家的最爱
because he left as everyone's favorite,
我敢肯定关于我的消息传出去了
and I'm sure word got out about, you know...me.
我只是不想让他觉得被取代了
I just didn't want him to feel displaced.
好了  让一让  大个儿
Okay. Excuse me, big guy.
大家都有礼物哦
Gifts for everyone.
安吉拉  这是刚从阿奴拉达普勒带来的
Angela, this is fresh from Anuradhapura.
凯伦
And, uh, Karen,
这个要和印度薄饼搭配吃哦
you might want to eat some chapati with that.
这是给...
And this is for, um --
-她叫玛西亚  -玛西亚
- It's Marcia. - Marcia!
当然啦  我知道的
Right, of course. I knew that.
我刚才满脑子肯定都是西班牙语
I must have been having a "Senor" moment.
某人总是如此
Somebody's always on.
这是谁干的
Who did this?
出什么事了
What happened?
有人把我的包摔到地上
Somebody knocked my bag down
摔坏了我的手机
and broke my phone.
莉莉  你知道是怎么回事吗
Lily, do you know anything about this?
他干的
He did it.
乔
Joe.
是啊  我要去玩了
Yep. I'm going to go and play.
她撒谎了
She lies.
乔怎么会把包从桌子上推下去
How could Joe pull a bag off a table?
他都不会走路
He can't even walk.
我去和她谈谈
I'll talk to her.
为什么是你
Why you?
因为你是个知道怎么
Because you're such a businessman
和别人谈话的生意人吗
that knows how to talk to people?
相信我  我跟她谈完之后
Trust me. When I get done talking to her,
她不但会承认错误
not only will she have confessed to the crime,
我还可能卖给她一个橱柜
I might even sell her a closet.
我记得有次
I remember my buddies
小伙伴们和我在玩石头大战
and I were playing rock war once.
那是个游戏
That's a game
我们把石头丢到对方的脑袋上
where you chuck rocks at each other's heads.
能出什么事啊  对吧
What could go wrong, right?
我把一块石头砸到了
I put one through the window
我爸漫步者车的窗户上
of my old man's Rambler,
他觉得是我的小弟弟干的
and he thought my baby brother did it.
我无法接受
I couldn't take it,
告诉他是我干的
and I told him I did it.
坦白的感觉棒极了
It felt so good to confess,
我爸爸很为我感到骄傲
and my old man was so proud of me,
我甚至都没被他责罚
I didn't even get in any trouble.
知道吗
Y-you know?
是乔干的
Joe did it.
她很厉害
She's good.
好好看看  学着点
Watch and learn.
我觉得她不吃你
I don't think that cleavage thing
露乳沟这一套吧
is gonna work with this one.
我又不是只会这一招
That's not my only trick.
好啊  莉莉
Hola, Lily.
外公去哪儿了
Where did grandpa go?
别担心杰
Don't worry about Jay.
现在这里只有我和你
It's only you and me here now.
告诉我
So, tell me.
你最喜欢哪个
Which one of these is your favorite?
没关系
Fine.
慢慢来
One by one,
它们都会消失
they will disappear.
或早或晚
Sooner or later,
我们会找到你最爱的那个
we'll get to the one that you love.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
他是中介之王
he's the emperor of escrow.
他太棒了
He puts the toot in tooter.
大家鼓掌欢迎
Let's put your hands together for
菲尔・邓菲
Phil Dunphy!
感谢这么好的司仪
Thanks for the kind introduction,
也就是我
me.
不像前几年
Now, unlike past years...
我不会再站在这
I'm not gonna stand up here
一直冲你们叽哩呱啦
and talk your ears off.
不  女士们先生们
No, ladies and gentlemen.
应该给你们点好东西
You deserve more.
今年
This year,
我要把词都唱出来
I'm gonna sing them off.
我要卖*
*I'm selling away
周六挂出一间房子开卖*
*Set an open house for Saturday
经纪人们的聚会*
*A gathering of agents
出现在大篷车*
*Appeared in caravan
我刚刚离婚*
*I'm a new divorce
我现在需要间房子*
*Now I need a house
可以让我养猫*
*That's cat-friendly
人们说伟大的艺术家
They say the greats
绝不会让任何事情影响表演
never let anything affect their performance.
或许这些伟人没有女儿
Well, maybe the greats never had a daughter
在你计划好的五次实时台上换装中的
who checked out during the third of five planned
第三次时走神
real-time, mid-performance wardrobe changes.
我不得不说
I'm not gonna lie.
这让我丧失了信心
It knocked me off my game.
在板子上*
*On the board
这是表演的一部分吗
Is this part of it?
不是
No.
这不是表演的一部分
It's not part of it.
在法学院
In law school,
温迪・柯克就有点容易情绪激动
Wendy Kirk could be a little intense.
我一直希望她会越来越温柔  可是
I always hoped that she'd soften over time, but...
有些人会向相反方向发展
...some people go the other way.
这地方是个噩梦
This place is a nightmare.
情况很糟糕
The conditions are deplorable,
大家都不应该
and no one should have to suffer
每天遭受这样的虐待
this kind of abuse on a daily basis.
什么暴君像这样完全不尊重人命啊
What kind of tyrant has such utter disregard for human life?
我干不下去了
I can't do this.
你必须干下去
You have to.
温迪需要听到
Wendy needs to hear it.
是啊  可我紧张  要是她
Yeah, but I'm nervous. You know, what if she --
-米奇尔  -是  你好
- Mitchell. - Yes! Hi!
我刚刚想到一个好主意
I just had a great idea.
我觉得你最适合培训雷克斯了
I think you would be the perfect person to groom Rex.
[Groom有清洗和培训两个意思]
什么
E-excuse me?
我只是觉得他真的会
I just think he'd really respond
和你这样的人产生共鸣
to someone like you, you know?
你不介意吧
Y-you don't mind, right?
不不  怎么会
Uh, uh, no. No, not at all.
太好了  谢谢
Great. Thanks.
麻烦你过去自我介绍一下吧
Will you go over and introduce yourself?
自我介  好吧
I-intro-- okay.
-好的  -谢谢
- Okay. Yeah. - Thank you.
你好  我是米奇尔
Hello. I'm Mitchell.
显然这现在是我的工作了
And, apparently, this is my job now.
天呐  你真臭
Oh, god, you smell.
大家都在看我
People are looking at me.
因为你让我把你打扮得很漂亮
That's because you let me make you beautiful.
别瞎说  我漂亮吗
Stop it. Am I?
你很美
Yes, you are.
玩得开心
Have fun.
去吧去吧
Go. Go.
德鲁  你好  德鲁
Drew. Hey, Drew.
玩得开心吗
Having fun?
开心  还好吧
"Fun"? Uh...okay.
德鲁  德鲁  听我说
Oh, Drew. Drew, listen.
我和菲尔今晚会很晚才回家
Phil and I are gonna be out really late tonight,
所以你开车带艾丽克斯回去时
so there will not be an adult at the house
家里没有大人
when you drop Alex off,
知道我什么意思吗
if you know what I mean.
是的  别担心
Yeah, don't worry.
我会开车送她回去
I'll, uh-- I'll drop her off,
我不会进屋的
and I won't go in.
大房子
Well... big house,
还有  可爱的女儿
you know... cute daughter--
我不反对你送她进门
I would not be opposed to you walking her in,
在我们回家前陪着她
keeping her company until we get back.
我刚说了
Like I said,
我们很晚才回家
we will not be back until late.
我听明白了  邓菲太太
I hear you, Mrs. Dunphy.
你可以相信我
You can trust me.
不得不相信你啊  因为我们
Well, gonna have to trust you because we have no way
无法知道你会干些什么
of knowing what you're gonna get up to.
这样  要是你的车挡在车道上
In fact, if your car is blocking the driveway,
我就鸣两次笛
I'll just honk twice
然后等你出来
and wait for you to come out.
-好的  -很好
- Okay. - Okay.
去找她吧  小伙子  快去
Go get her, tiger. Come on.
干得好  塔克
Nice job, Tucker.
你做了很多
I mean, you made so many choices
我不可能做出的选择
that I never would have made,
但大部分效果不错
but a lot of them are working.
这样啊
Oh, well, you know,
我就是看你策划的
I just watched the videos
很多很多舞会视频
of the many, many dances you planned
然后就想出了这么一个主意
and just built off that one on idea.
孩子们
Hey, kids!
我的小甜心们
There are my little chalupas!
你对朗达做了什么
Um, what did you do to Rhonda?
我把她整干净了
I cleaned her up.
不  你毁了她
No, you broke her.
我不喜欢这样的她
I hate her like this.
她美极了
She looks fantastic.
对你来说是
To you!
把她变回去  这样很伤脑筋
Fix her. Ugh, it confuses me.
卢克啊
Oh, Luke.
"家里没人"
"The house will be empty"?
你在给我拉皮条
You are pimping me out!
你俩显然喜欢对方
It is clear that the two of you like one another.
有时需要有人推你们一把
Sometimes, you need a little nudge.
你可是行为监督人啊
Well, you're a chaperone!
快消失吧
Just disappear!
这舞会不是你该来的地方
This dance is not for you!
你真走运  居然是水
You're lucky that's water.
该死
Damn it.
她已经生了一个小时的闷气了
She's been stewing in there for an hour.
我们不如锁上门
I say let's lock the door,
拉了电闸
cut the power.
让她意识到我们态度有多严肃
Let's show her that we mean business.
我们先采取温和点的手段吧  监狱长
Let's try the joint approach first..."Gitmo."
[Gitmo: 古巴臭名昭著的关塔那摩湾监狱]
我们仔细思考了一下你的供词
Okay, we've been going over your story,
不怎么有说服力
and it doesn't add up.
我放包的地方对乔来说太高了
My purse was too high for Joe to reach.
他已经能够着这里了
He's tall enough to reach up here.
他为了拿到我的小动物们
He knocked over the baby powder
把婴儿爽身粉碰倒了
trying to get my stuffed animals.
我不信
Not buying it.
看  这还有他走过的脚印呢
Look. You can see the footprints where he walked.
走
Walk?
莉莉  莉莉  莉莉
Lily, Lily, Lily.
乔还不会走路呢
Joe can't walk.
他在我面前走了
He does for me.
所以你有办法让他走路吗
So, you have ways of making him walk?
莉莉  就承认是你做的吧
Lily, just admit that you did it.
过来  乔
Come here, Joe.
像你之前做的那样
Come here like you did before.
宝贝  你在自找难堪
Honey, you're embarrassing yourself.
-过来  乔  -他不会走路
- Come here, Joe. - He can't walk.
他居然会走了
He's walking!
我之前点的那些蜡烛起作用了
The candles that I lit worked!
看他的步子迈得多大
Look at the stride on him.
他走得跟山羊一样稳健
He's as surefooted as a mountain goat.
我就说嘛
Told you.
真对不起我们怀疑你了
I'm so sorry that we doubted you.
不敢相信我居然这么幸运
Boy, did I get lucky.
在他学会说话之前
I'm going to blame everything on him
他都会是我的替罪羊
until he learns how to talk.
那个男人跳着华尔兹自以为是舞池之王
This guy waltzes in here like he's king of the dance
说什么帮助不发达地区建学校
after doing god knows what in Sri Lanka,
都不知道他在斯里兰卡干了什么勾当
building schools in underdeveloped areas.
都不知道他想干嘛
What does that even mean?
你对那个男人是不是有点太苛刻了
Is it possible that you're being a little hard on the man?
是我把他的二流舞会办成了年度盛事
I turned his two-bit dance into the event of the year.
看  小混混和书呆子
Look. Burnouts and dweebs
能这么和谐共处
hanging out together in harmony.
都是我的功劳
That is me.
我很遗憾  小卡
I'm sorry, Cam.
别替我遗憾
Oh, don't feel sorry for me.
马上就是教职员工舞蹈环节
Next is faculty dance.
卡普兰不会跳舞
Kaplan can't move.
都传到Tumblr上了
It's on his Tumblr.
[Tumblr: 微视频社交网站]
那是他的一大耻辱
It's his big shame.
相信我
Trust me.
他抢不走我的风头
He can't touch this.
好了  到了教职员工起舞的时候了
Okay, time now for the faculty dance.
老师们  上吧
Go, teachers.
你确定吗
Oh, are you sure?
停  现在是小卡秀场
Stop. It's "Cammer" Time.
不介意我也来跳吧  教练
Mind if I join you, coach?
休假期间
While on sabbatical,
我在斯里兰卡跟质多斯那学了点舞蹈
I learned a thing or two from Sri Lanka's own Chitrasena.
[质多斯那: 斯里兰卡舞蹈之父]
我不知道他是谁
I don't know who that is,
而且你说话的态度很讨人厌
and it's annoying when you say things
好像谁都应该知道他似的
like people are supposed to know!
看来那个可悲的孔雀男
That pathetic peacock of a man
是要跟我一战到底
was not going down without a fight.
我必须做出选择
I had a choice to make --
要么跳得比他好  要么比他大度
be the better dancer or the bigger man.
所以我离开了舞台
So, I stepped off the dance floor
做了最正确的选择
and made the obvious call.
你想吸引大家的注意力吗
You want to win over a crowd?
去邀请一位孤独的母亲共舞吧
Invite a lonely mom to dance.
她没有想到我这一招
She never saw it coming,
他也一样
and neither did he.
喂  老兄
Hey Senor.
学着点吧
You just got out-coached.
我尝试看向事物更积极的一面
I try and look on the bright side of things.
我是那种即使要给臭狗洗澡
I-I'm a doggy-bath-is-half-full
也依然乐观的人
kind of guy.
但我应该醒悟了
But it was time for me to open my eyes.
我的老板是个禽兽
I was working for a monster.
我来这里工作是为了替弱势群体说话
I came to this job to be the voice of the downtrodden.
可没想到弱势群体居然就是我的同事
Turns out those downtrodden were my co-workers,
他们迫切地需要屠龙的英雄
and they were desperate for a hero to slay their dragon.
各位  不好意思我来晚了
Hey, guys. Sorry I'm late.
雷克斯  你跟米奇尔处得怎么样
Um, Rex, how's it going with Mitchell?
新来的那个吗
The new guy?
我还没见过他呢
I haven't met him yet.
真奇怪  我让他来自我介绍了啊
That's weird. I asked him to introduce himself.
有人看到我的狗了吗
hey, has anybody seen my dog?
皮克希
Pixie!
她来了
Oh, there she is.
温迪  不好意思
Okay, Wendy, I'm sorry.
我有话想跟你说
I-I have something to say to you,
一些在座诸位都不敢说的话
something that everybody else here is afraid to say.
我知道你现在做的都是好事
Now, I know you're fighting the good fight,
可是这也不能成为你如此对待别人的借口
but that is no excuse for the way you treat people.
不过这倒有可能导致
T-that actually might be one of the reasons
你没有亲密爱人
that you have no personal life
毕竟谁也不想回家面对
because who wants to come home
一个冷血无情的恶棍
to a-a cold, emotionless...thug?
你  你都在说什么啊
W-what are you talking about?
我是一名经验丰富值得尊重的律师
I am an experienced, respected attorney,
可是上班第一天
and on my first day,
你居然让我去给雷克斯洗澡
you asked me to bathe Rex.
我有点无法忍受
I'm not comfortable with that.
我也无法忍受
And I'm not comfortable with that,
可我还是做了
but I did it.
好吧  那是皮克希
Okay, that's Pixie.
这才是雷克斯
This is Rex,
我让你培训的实习生
the intern I asked you to groom.
好吧  这是我的错
And that is my mistake,
我负全责
and I own that.
可即使那样
But that is still no excuse
你也没有理由因为他
for the way that you tore into him
昨天的穿着对他大吼大叫
for the outfit he wore yesterday.
我当时是为了他给我挑的衣服生气
I was talking about the outfit he picked out for me.
很明显  我招了世界上唯一一个
Apparently, I have the one gay intern in the world
没有时尚嗅觉的男同性恋实习生
with absolutely no fashion sense.
我不了解当时的背景情况
I was unaware of -- of this dynamic.
可是我  我不是一个人  对吧
But I-I-I'm not alone here, all right?
这屋里肯定还有别人觉得你是
There are people in this room who feel that you are --
我们应该怎么说呢
How did we say it? --
你是个毫不尊重他人的暴君
you are a tyrant with no regard for human life.
听起来像我那个恶房东案子的总结陈词
That sounds like my summation for the slum-lord case.
什么  你写完了吗
Oh, hey, you finished it?
写得超棒
It's wonderful.
可是他不好意思给你看
But he's nervous to show you.
你怎么对自己那么苛刻呢
Why are you so hard on yourself?
好吧  那  那么
Okay, but w-w-what --
你强迫我们周日工作又怎么说
what about you making us work on sundays?
是在说  周日晚去我家烧烤吗
That -- the night of my barbecue?
丹
Dan?
你怎么还在这里
What are you still doing here?
今天是你的结婚纪念日  快回家
It's your anniversary! Go home!
天哪  告诉我这不是真的
Oh, god. This isn't happening.
不  不  她很疯狂
No, no. She's -- she's crazy.
我看到她攻击自动售货机
I mean, I saw her attack the vending machine.
自从丹尼斯把它弄坏以后就只能那样用了
That's the only way it works since Dennis broke it.
丹尼斯就是之前用我那间办公室的人吗
Dennis is the guy whose office I took?
是的  他曾是那个机器最好的客户
Yeah, he was the machine's best customer
直到他开始跑步
until he started running.
有一天他说  他一定要离开  否则
One day, he said he's got to get out or --
他就会死  好吧  好吧
He would die. Okay. Okay.
温迪
Wendy, um...
我也许应该向你道歉
I-I might owe you a little bit of an apology,
对不起
so I'm sorry.
很明显  这里每个人都很爱你
Um, clearly, everybody here loves you,
我之前把一切都搞错了
and I-I was wrong about everything.
所以  对不起
So...I'm sorry.
你知道吗  你也不是全搞错了
You know, you -- you weren't wrong about everything.
我虽然拿这事开玩笑  但你是对的
I mean, look, I do joke about it, but you're right.
我孤单一人
I'm alone.
这也不是第一次有人说我冷漠
And that is not the first time that someone has called me cold.
我的那些卵子
Okay, those eggs...
那些卵子取出来就是冷冻的
those eggs came out of me frozen.
而且我还这么高
And I'm impossibly tall.
即使我能找到一个人来爱我
And even if I could find somebody to love me,
他们也够不着啊
they -- they wouldn't be able to reach.
不  别这样
No -- hey, hey. Come on.
你是个很了不起的女性
You're -- you're an amazing woman.
她是个了不起的女性
She's an amazing woman.
而且  你是个榜样
And you -- you're a-a role model.
你是个英雄
You're a hero.
我是个六尺高的英雄
I'm a 6-foot hero.
不  别这样
No. Come on.
你周围的人都爱你
You're surrounded by people who love you.
有丹还有雷克斯
Here's Dan and Rex.
还有我  过来
Me. Come here.
还有挂在那里的塞缪尔・杰克逊
All the way up to Samuel L. Jackson there.
那是你妈妈戴着袋鼠牌帽子  是吗
That's your mother in a Kangol hat, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
你确定你自己在干什么吗  塔德
Um, are you sure you know what you're doing, Tad?
我知道你来自抵押医生[机构]  但是
I know you're the Mortgage Doctor, but --
有人问  这里有医生吗
Someone said, "Is there a doctor in the house?"
难道我不应该站出来吗
Was I supposed to not get up?
爸爸  你需要我帮你脱掉裙子吗
Hey, dad. You need any help out of that dress?
除非你想看我
Not unless you want to see me
一丝不挂只穿着一个新年婴儿纸尿裤
in nothing but a baby new year's diaper.
那是你在发短信时
That was the big finish
我要唱的歌的结尾重头戏
to the song you were texting through.
我就收了一条短信  我看了大部分节目
Hey, I got one text. I saw most of the show --
我们这就走了
We're leaving, okay?
你能回桌子上
Could you just go to the table
拿我的钥匙和包吗
and grab my keys and purse?
好吧
Fine.
你想聊聊吗
You want to talk about it?
你到底能假扮几种医生
How many kinds of fake doctor are you?
好了  到了揭晓今晚大奖的时刻了
Okay, time for the big award of the night,
"年地经"奖[年度地产经纪]
The ROY...
我都不知道自己为什么生她的气
I don't even know why I'm mad at her.
也许只是因为她整晚都显得很无聊
Probably just 'cause she was so bored all night.
也许你感觉自己不被她接纳
Maybe you're feeling rejected?
是我自己的错
It's my own fault.
我给了自己一个错误的希望
I built up this hope
以为她会愿意追随我进入地产业
that she'd want to follow me into real estate.
菲尔・邓菲
...Phil Dunphy.
她现在有自己的生活了
She's got her own life now.
我只是不知道我们还能在哪里有联系
I just don't know where we connect anymore.
你赢了
You won.
-什么  -是啊
- What?! - Yeah.
扶我起来
Help me up!
我们都知道
As we all know,
菲尔今晚出了点小意外
Phil had a little accident tonight,
但我们很乐意
but we're happy to accept
-替他接受这个奖项  -等等  等等
- this award on his behalf.  - Wait, wait, wait.
等等  等等
Wait, w-w-w-w-wait!
我来
I got this.
大家好  我是
Hi. I'm, uh,
我是海莉  菲尔的女儿
I'm haley, Phil's daughter.
爸爸  你赢得了"年地经"
Dad, you won the ROY!
你们都知道他是个出色的地产经纪
You all know him as an amazing realtor,
但我知道他还是世界上最棒的爸爸
but I know him as the world's greatest dad.
据我所知
As far as I'm concerned,
他也是年度最佳父亲
he's the dad of the year,
"年爸爸"奖得主
the "DOY."
今晚真的很遗憾
It really is a shame
你们没有听完他的完整演出
that you didn't hear the rest of his act tonight.
但我有听过他排练
I-I heard him rehearsing it.
你们哪位是J.J.・麦卡宾
Which one of you is J.J. McCubbin?
快速问答  J.J.
Oh. Hey, quick question, J.J. --
为什么一个好的抵押就像
Why is a great mortgage rate
你老婆的床上表现
like your wife in bed?
一个月一次还低利息[兴趣]
Once a month and low interest.
你笑什么  斯基普・伍斯奴
What are you laughing at, Skip Woosnum?
自从你加入海军后
You haven't seen a commission
就没收过佣金了[服役]
since you joined the navy.
她真是棒极了
She is killing it.
这才是我闺女
That's my girl.
但我会在"海军"上加重语气
I would have hit the word "Navy" harder.
还有什么  还有什么来着
What else? What else?
玛格利特・福曼也来了
Oh! Margaret Furman's here.
我要提醒一下她的男伴
Little heads-up to her date --
她比房利美公司拥有更多资不抵债住房
She's been upside-down in more houses than Fannie Mae.
或者说  房利一定会美
Or, in her case, Fannie definitely will.
我们都希望别人看到自己最好的一面
We all want people to think the best of us...
所以有时我们会隐藏一些事
So sometimes we cover things up
以保护自己
to protect ourselves.
但我们不必害怕
But we don't have to be afraid...
因为真相永远是一件好事
Because the truth is always a good thing.
真相让我们自由
The truth sets us free...
让我们更亲近
...brings us closer.
你想不想告诉我们
So, do you want to tell us
乔的鞋怎么会穿错脚了呢
How Joe's shoes ended up on the wrong feet?
看来小家伙学会了自己穿鞋
I guess the little guy knows how to put on his own shoes.
开始吧  伙计  你能行
There you go, buddy. You got this.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
既然乔会走路了
Since Joe can walk now,
我觉得他应该分担些家务了
I figured he should be doing a few chores.
稳一点  大小伙
Steady, big guy!
家务  什么样的
Chores? What kind of --
他来了
There he is.
好孩子
Attaboy!
啤酒  你疯了吗
A beer? Are you crazy?
你去哪  你想来点吗
Where you going? You want some?
他也可以给你拿
He'll bring it to you.
我简直不敢相信你竟然教他做那种事
I can't believe that you're teaching him to do that.
看完第二段再评论吧
Wait till you see part two.
好孩子
Attaboy.
放心吧  是我自己
Relax, it was me.